Some people say the number one enemy to a fly fisher is wind.
It's not really, but for this demonstration, we will cover wind.
So, when the wind is coming towards you, you want to get underneath the wind, so now I will demonstrate that for you, o.k.
We do that mainly with the body and dropping the rod.
Up, now see how we get underneath.
We go low to the ground.
By doing that, we cut underneath the wind.
O.k, in relationship to the wind coming from your back, we just covered what if the wind is coming to your face.
O.k, we're going to use the same analogy, now, except now, it's going to be in reverse.
This time to beat the wind coming against our back, we need to go low in our back cast, come up, and then go down in our forward cast.
So, it's low, come up and make your regular conventional cast because essentially, the wind is going to carry it through.
I'll demonstrate with my hand, lift, flip up, and make the cast.
This is essentially called an elliptical or circular cast.
See the elliptical motion of the hand?
Underneath the wind, and stop and make your forward cast.
Now, I'll demonstrate.
Low, there's our cast.
See how the rod goes low?
And, we make our perfect stop.
The wind is going to carry our forward cast.
So, it's, and that's how we are able to fish in all types of wind.
You will be a good fly fisher.